

ABOUT ME

My name is Matthew Callahan and I am a software engineer in Phoenix, Arizona. I have over ten years of experience in web and desktop software development using Scrum, Kanban, and XP agile methodologies. Learning the dynamic landscape of computer programming is my passion.

CONTACT

EMAIL:

matthew.callahan@outlook.com

PHONE:

630-988-1555

HOMEPAGE:

mfcallahan.com

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

GITHUB:

github.com/mfcallahan

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

KEY SKILLS

C# (.NET & .NET Core) JavaScript ES6+

TypeScript

Angular

Node.js

Python

Git

ArcGIS

Azure

MATTHEW CALLAHAN

EDUCATION



University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Systems

EXPERIENCE

Staff Engineer, Republic Services | Scottsdale, Arizona

May 2019 - Present

- Lead a team of eight developers and testers, overseeing talent development, skill set improvement, and acting as a mentor to all team members.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture for greenfield development (.NET & .NET Core back end/Angular front end).
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage on all apps, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and currently leading effort to refactor all applications to follow these guidelines.
- Technologies used: .NET, .NET Core, C#, Angular, Node.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, SQL Server, ArcGIS.

Senior GIS Developer, Republic Services | Scottsdale, Arizona

December 2018 - May 2019

- Web development, creating enterprise applications which focused on mapping and visualizing data to assist in daily business operations (ASP.NET, Angular).
- Desktop application development for GIS analysis (ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Implemented a uniform Git branching strategy and code review process for all application repositories.

Software Engineer, Carvana | Tempe, Arizona

February 2018 - December 2018

- Back end development to create and maintain the APIs and microservices which powered carvana.com (C#, .NET & .NET Core).
- Front end development to create a mobile responsive user interface for a vehicle inventory search engine (JavaScript ES6+, React/Redux, AngularJS).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver the best UX.

Application Developer, CBRE | Phoenix, Arizona

January 2011 – February 2018

- Developed web applications which provided data analysis and mapping tools to real estate brokers and their clients (ASP.NET MVC).
- Developed desktop applications for GIS data analysis (C# .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Employee of the year "MVP" award, 2012.

GIS Technician, CBRE | Phoenix, Arizona

March 2008 - January 2011

- Developed scripts and desktop GIS tools to automate tasks and improve workflow efficiency of GIS Technicians.
- Created custom maps, demographic reports, and market research reports for commercial real estate brokers, affording them the ability to make well informed decisions and best serve their clients.
- Employee of the Quarter, 1st quarter 2009.